

Pran Kishore Mobile App Developer (iOS) Kolkata, West Bengal, India

Profile

Mobile application developer with 10+ years of experience focused on iOS. Dev Ops & Design enthusiast. Design awardwinning, more than a million downloaded apps on the app store. AWS Business professional, keen on cloud and server-side programming

Experience

Senior Software Engineer (iOS) - EPAM Systems Inc. Sep 2020 - Present

Tech Lead (iOS) - Optimize IT Systems Pvt. Ltd. Mar 2019 - Sep 2020

Associate Consultant - Atos India Pvt. Ltd. May 2015 – March 2019

Software Engineer – Customer First InfonetPvt. Ltd Jan 2014 – May 2015

Software Engineer – Micronix Technologies Pvt.Ltd. Jun 2013 – Jan 2014

Education

B.Tech CSE- West Bengal University of Technology 2008-2012 - DGPA - 7.28

Heritage Institute of Technology, Kolkata, West Bengal

10 +2 Sc. CBSE 2004-2006 - 63%

ST. Josephs Public School, Samastipur, Bihar

10 th ICSE 2003 - 75%

ST. Paul's High School, Patna, Bihar

Passion

Writing code for iOS

Case Study & Estimation

Testing (Xcode Automated)

Sever Side / AWS Server-less

Skill Set

Xcode 15

Swift / Objective C

CI/CD

Sketch / XD

Languages Known

English

Hindi

Bengali

Contact Details

7, Mukherjee House, North Purbachal Garden Road P.O. Haltu Kolkata -700078, India

kishorepran@gmail.com

+91-9330568475

Skype: prankishore19

Core iOS Skills

Objective C / Swift

Design patterns MVC, Delegation, Singleton.Concurrency management, collection types. ARC, Optional Chaining, Protocols, Extensions, Generics.

Frameworks

Address book, Assets Library, Core Graphics / Image /Location / Text/ Video /Motion, Foundation, Health Kit, Map Kit, Media player, Sql Lite 3.0, Security, Social. XCTest for unit & UI testing.

Features

App extensions, Handoff, UIKit Dynamics, Background fetch ,Siri kit, Size classes, Ineractive APNS, Local notifications , Custom Gesture recognizers,

Core Services

GCD, In app purchase, SQL Lite, Core data.

App Management

Generating Certificate & provisioning, iTunes connect configuration App store upload, test flight distribution both internal & external, App analytics.

Xcode / Others

Integration of third party frameworks via COCOA PODS, Instruments, Time profiling, allocation, memory leaks, LLDB, Custom breakpoints, View Debugger, Touch ID, Source editor extensions, Barometer, Three Axis Gyro, Accelerometer. Ethical Hacking - Jailbreaking iPhone, MTM (Man in the Middile attack), Reverse Engineering Binary.

Top Projects

Deutsche Bank Mobile

Mobile Banking application. Red dot design award winner. Rated 4.6 out of 5

URL :- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/deutsche-bank-mobile/id1040475847

DBS digibank Singapore

Mobile Banking application.

URL :- https://apps.apple.com/sg/app/dbs-digibank-sg/id1068403826

Links



https://github.com/kishorepran



https://twitter.com/pran_kishore



https://www.linkedin.com/in/pran-kishore/



https://medium.com/@kishorepran

Other Skills

High learning curve, Complex Problem solving

Experience in version controlsystems like GIT & SVN, with tools(Source tree) &CMD

Working in a high performing scrum team at Deutsche Bank, Germany delivering app update every 2-3 months.

Passion for taking dev ops role to facilitate team members achieving high productivity. Implemented on board Git lab instance on ubuntu 14.04, connected with CI/CD

Extra activities

Teaching Mathematics to students of class 11th& 12th

Took part in swimming competition in non professional swimmers category at ILSS Kolkata

Other Projects

Canadian Tire: Shop Smarter

The Canadian Tire app makes it easy to shop deals, activate Triangle Rewards offers, earn Canadian Tire Money ®, check in-store product inventory, and find weekly flyer deals.

URL:- https://apps.apple.com/ca/app/canadian-tire-shop-smarter/id403884878

Seller - Canadian Tire Corporation, Limited

Qatar Airways

Book flights, manage your booking, check in and take full control of your journey with the Qatar Airways mobile app.

URL :- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/qatar-airways/id581264644

Seller - Fast Fwd Multimedia Ltd.

Kauai Beach Guide

Find your perfect beach using the Kauai Beach Guide. The fully interactive GPS-enabled map, filtered searches, detailed beach information and up-to-date ocean, weather, and tide reports.

URL :- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/kauai-beach-guide/id425743908

Seller - Beach Toolz, LLC

IndiaMoneyMart - P2P Lending

IndiaMoneyMart (IMM) is a P2P lending and borrowing platform where its registered lenders offer affordable unsecured loan to its registered borrowers/loan applicants.

URL :- https://apps.apple.com/us/app/indiamoneymart-p2p-lending/id1347109712

Seller - Fair Vinimay Services Pvt Ltd.

CGFirst

This corporate governance app where client's of CGFirst will be able to download the app and will digitize the whole process. Features: Both client and CGfirst personnel may schedule meetings, people will be able to see meeting details and set their RSVP status. All documents in different formats (word, PDF, jpg) will be saved to the cloud for sharing. PDF's handled via world's leading PDF kit – PSPDF will all features such as editing annotations etc.

URL :- https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/cgfirst-ipad-edition/id656360855?mt=8

Seller - Fast Fwd Multimedia Ltd.

Retired Apps

Leica confocal microscopy (Leica Microsystems)

URL:- https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/leica-confocal-microscopy/id896704331?mt=8

FastAnalytics

https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/fast-analytics/id467379850?ls=1&mt=8

Hear and See

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/asm-wshahd/id1001907602?mt=8

Awards

Customer First InfonetPvt. Ltd

Received 'Made a Difference' award for achieving highest customer satisfaction for working in a dedicated hiring model for offshore client and managing overall app lifecycle, from planning to production.

Atos India Pvt. Ltd

Received 'Atos Expert' award for boosting innovation in the company, further improve R&D, setting up highest standards in project delivery to end customer playing key roles from planning to production.

References

Dr. Subhashis Majumder, Head of Department, Computer Science and Engineering

Heritage Institute of Technology, Kolkata. Chowbaga Road, Anandapur,

Kolkata 700 107

Email: subhashis.majumder@heritageit.edu

Phone no 9830044136

Debanjan Majumdar - Project Lead

Indus Net Technologies, Salt lake, Sector V, Kolkata 700 091

Email: debanjan.majumdar@gmail.com

Phone no 9748491834

Swarnali Nandy – Project Manager

Indus Net Technologies, Salt lake, Sector V, Kolkata 700 091

Email: swarnali.nandi@indusnet.co.in

Phone no 9830170921

Chiranjib Banerjee - Mobility Consultant

Atos India Pvt. Ltd., Salt lake, Sector V, Kolkata 700 091

Email: chiranjib.banerjee@atos.net

Phone no 9433258064